Dear Recruitment Officer,

Re: Application for the Position of an Environmental Engineer or Scientist

I am writing in response to your advertisement for an Environmental Engineer or Scientist. I am a Doctoral student at the Department of Civil Engineering in Queen's University (Graduation: April 2019). Having acquired over three years' experience conducting experimental research relevant to the fields of Civil and Materials Engineering, with emphasis on buried infrastructure deterioration and rehabilitation., I would love to apply my skills to this role.

I am captivated by the opportunity this role provides, to work alongside experts across various fields on challenging and diverse projects. Due to my desire to acquire knowledge and conduct research in a variety of fields related to science and engineering, I have attained a diverse academic and professional background and have completed coursework in Chemical, Materials, Mechanical and Civil Engineering. I believe this will be an asset to the role, as I have learnt how to apply fundamental skills such as; critical thinking, qualitative and quantitative analysis, and problem solving, in various fields. This has enabled me to excel in different academic disciplines and conduct high quality research in various fields. I am also a fast learner and have excellent interpersonal skills.

To develop my presentation and communication skills to a wide range of audience, I have presented at various academic conferences and delivered undergraduate guest lectures at the Civil and Mechanical Engineering departments at Queen's University. I have also participated in various professional development workshops such as; Skills of Communication and Essentials of Productive Teams.

With my skills and academic background, I believe I would be well equipped in carrying out the expected duties efficiently. I would be glad to provide any additional information needed. I thank you for taking the time to go through my CV, as I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely, Titilope Adebola

TITILOPE ADEBOLA

Mobile: 343 333 6527

Email: titilope.adebola@gmail.com, 15tooa@queensu.ca

Profile

I have over three years' experience conducting experimental research relevant to the fields of Civil and Materials Engineering, with emphasis on infrastructure deterioration and rehabilitation. I am a highly motivated individual with a penchant for excellence, capable of working independently as well as in a team, meeting rigid deadlines while exceeding expectations.

Core Skills

- Qualitative and Quantitative Data Analysis
- Technical Report Writing
- Proficiency in Engineering tools (including AutoCAD)
- Materials Characterization Techniques
- Mechanical Testing and Instrumentation
- Detail Oriented

- Organization and Time Management
- Public Speaking
- Interpersonal Skills (Team Work)
- Multitasking
- Microsoft Office
- Oral and Written Communication

Work Experience

Research Assistant | Department of Civil Engineering, Queen's University September 2015 – Present

- Manage multiple research projects related to the design and conducting of scientific experiments in collaboration with industry partners.
- Develop experimental testing procedures and provide in-depth analysis of obtained results under minimal supervision.
- Prepare articles for submission to academic journals and conferences and present research findings at international conferences, stakeholder meetings and community events.
- Delegated as a representative of Queen's University to promote graduate research at communityevents, including to the Mayor of Kingston.
- Initiated and managed tools for effective scheduling of laboratory activities by graduate students within the department, thus improving their productivity.

Graduate Teaching Assistant | Department of Civil Engineering, Queen's University January 2016 - Present

- Develop assessment tools to evaluate students' performance in undergraduate level courses.
- Design teaching materials alongside course instructors to improve students' learning and engagement.
- Deliver guest lectures and facilitate weekly tutorials to a class size of over 60 students.
- Train new teaching assistants on the effective delivery of course materials and the proper use of laboratory equipment.
- Respond to student inquiries and concerns related to the course.

Consultant | Community Foundation for Kingston & Area

September 2017 - March 2018

- Worked as part of an interdisciplinary team responsible for developing an action plan to solve an ongoing marketing problem faced by the foundation.
- Conducted extensive qualitative and quantitative research to evaluate the scope of the problem.
- Performed small-scale tests within controlled populations to assess the feasibility of our proposed recommendations and the potential for scaling-up.
- Provided recommendations and implementation strategies based on research findings to help the foundation improve their marketing techniques.

Industrial Trainee | Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation

March – June 2015

- Worked as part of a team responsible for the start-up of the Linear Alkyl Benzene (LAB) production plant after a ten year shut-down.
- Attended to operational problems encountered in the plant.

Volunteer Experience

Community Service Coordinator | Civil Graduate Student Society

May 2016 - September 2017

- First elected official to assume this position in the department.
- Identified opportunities for students to engage with the community through volunteering.
- Established partnerships between the department and community partners within the Kingston community, such as Habitat for Humanity, Loving Spoonful and Big Brothers Big Sisters of Canada.
- Managed all aspects of the event planning, including marketing, transportation logistics, feeding and student role assignment.

Education

Queen's University – Kingston, OntarioDoctoral degreeSeptember 2015 – 2019Civil EngineeringAfrican University of Science and Technology – NigeriaMaster's degreeJuly 2013 – December 2014Materials Science and EngineeringAmerican University of Nigeria - NigeriaBachelor's degreeJanuary 2009 - December 2011(Honours)Petroleum Chemistry